[Music]
you're listening to the AI native Dev
brought to you by
Tesla and welcome back to the AI native
Dev on today's episode we're doing
another special episode guy and myself
Simon Maple are back together again and
we're doing a monthly Roundup so welcome
to the Roundup guide welcome to you as
well
it's fun our first monthly R up we we'll
see find the Rhythm really for these
things how we talk about all the sort of
the fun episodes the learnings from the
month on it get an opportunity maybe to
uh voice some opinions we really try to
use the time for the uh opinions of the
smart people we're getting onto the
podcast but uh we do have some opinions
of our own so yeah absolutely and
talking about getting back into the
Rhythm we had that long gap between a
previous podcast and and currently this
one how did you find uh doing quite a
few sessions I think we've done we've
recorded close to 10 sessions already
many of which are already out uh some
are coming very soon after this episode
so how did you find getting back in it's
like riding a bicycle it yeah but it's
actually it's super fun I always find
what's not to like really about this
it's an opportunity to uh find
interesting people and ask them you know
questions that you find interesting yeah
and just get to air that and share that
with the world on it and super fun and
continuously humbling to see people
willing to share their learning
learnings and all that it's it's a live
world there's a certain amount of
knowledge is power or some advantage to
it so I always find it uh gratifying
there's like an element of gratitude in
in having people share it but also every
single conversation I have a hard time
finishing it because I have more things
that I want to ask do you know what I I
find it really fun to just chat to smart
people and I I use this podcast as a bit
of an excuse really because there are a
ton of smart people that it just sounds
weird me just like creeping into their
DM saying hey can we just chat for an
hour about cool stuff but this having
this podcast is really nice to be able
to say hey I've got a podcast and we're
going to talk about this would you love
to come on and just chat chat it's a
good social experiment you should see it
can you do something like that and like
never air the podcast no no no we're
this podcast how long can you drag that
on of having someone come along on your
podcast their quotes to listen no one
will trust us again guy yeah that's true
that's true it might be a short lft
strategy absolutely yeah we had fun we
had fun this this month and what we're
going to do the format of this monthly
episode is really going to grab some
themes really from a number of sessions
and episodes that that have been add
this month and we'll just talk about
some of our learnings by theme and we'll
jump into some quotes and talk about how
the various the various people who who
appeared on the podcast spoke to these
themes and yeah it should be a little
bit of fun and a nice recap really of of
the month so our first topic our first
theme then guy really was about how well
these products work obviously there are
a ton of different AI Tools in in in
various categories which we'll talk
about in just a sec as well some promise
far too much some promise well and
actually deliver with nice road maps in
the future of how they can improve and
so forth but the rarest pieces to this I
guess one major piece is the evaluation
in terms of understanding whether a
model answers to a prompt work well or
not and in in various different
scenarios right what was your take on
that yeah I think what shown through
very clearly is that it's very hard to
know whether these products work and
it's interesting how consistent that was
and I think you don't really learn to
appreciate that until you try to build
an llm based product it's very part of
it is that it's very hard to even just
know up front whether it worked so even
if you know what is it that you're
trying to achieve the answer is not
always as robust whether you're
generating code or tests or whatever it
is did you generate to the right thing
did you understand uh the right question
all of those are very hard to do they're
even harder to do in in breadth and I
think what became very clear is that
it's also hard to anticipate how they
will react in the next one I think Dez
said it best when he described the
difference between their sort of good
case and what they call the torture test
everyone should have a set of torture
tests in their test suit right I I I
think now it's like it's a it's a
necessity we're going to have a torture
test
just for the name of it but uh it was
interesting because it was describing
both how you know first of all it's hard
to even Define the original set of tests
but those are the good cases and those
are as hard as they are the easiest
thing to do and also you can do them
maybe relatively quickly the real
challenge comes when you run through
these sort of torture tests of someone
coming along and wanting seven different
versions of of bits of information or
giving you 20 instructions in one
command yeah but then that even those
are not enough and that in practice you
to his words don't know if your product
works until you ship it yeah um and
that's super super hard um and this came
up in really a whole bunch of
conversations including some we haven't
shed yet
and it's something that we're feeling at
Tesla as well on the product front on it
trying to say okay if we were to
generate some piece of code if we were
to try and be on the journey to generate
some piece of code did we generate it
correctly or not um do you feel the
sentiment is the same do you feel like
we're all experienced in the same pain
or are we are we experiencing that
differently so for example from what Dez
was talking about there with the torture
tests really trying to be really trying
to have a set of T tests that is most
lifelike to to production is this the
same scenario that everyone is is really
faced with or are there variations on
that I think when you're trying to mimic
intelligence it's very hard to know
whether you have an intelligent answer
or not I've been doing this all my
career guys yeah yeah and you've still
not managed Intelligence on the I've got
close I think I'm close CL full
sometimes yeah I'm I'm I'm making those
attempts myself as well but when you try
to mimic intelligence it's hard to know
whether you indeed hit hit it the
correct chord right you to get it right
and the the broader the set of
possibilities the harder it is to to get
it right and how close your torture test
is to reality as well trying to almost
rerun existing prompts and existing what
users are doing to actually create that
set of torture tests and you can never
really if you were to contrast this to
to a wiiz Weg or like some form of of UI
there is a finite set of possibilities
and so you're even never going to
include that the other thing that Dez
actually phrased well was the notion of
a change like some when a new like in
this world it's not just your
capabilities that change it's also the
underlying Technologies right so you get
a new version of an nlm comes along
whatever state-ofthe-art that is and as
a tool provider because of the
difficulty in in assessing it you're
faced with sort of these two options
none of them are terribly exciting and
one is you just skew optimistic and you
throw in says hey let's hope this works
and it definitely is short-term gain uh
but it might be very risky it's almost a
marketing game right it's who it's it's
that first market and I think one of the
things that Dez said was when a new
model comes out he sees lots of
competitors and lots of others snap into
that new model OKAY 40's out let's snap
into let's snap into 40 it's a really
easy thing to change but it's a hard
thing to actually be able to assess
without snapping it into production
whether whether it's actually going to
improve be the same or even degradate
the behavior or the the functionality
the functionality and it's also tempting
to just throw it out there and that
makes it hard on the consumer side to be
able to take those tools because to
begin with as a consumer you also don't
know if they work but then if people
swap these models under you just because
in some cases they are very good it
makes it very hard we have Amy on our
team at at tessla who leads AI
engineering she talks a lot about the
Jagged Edge that is of AI they're
amazing at sometimes and then they're
like horrible at other times and that's
very felt but I guess the other option
is not that exciting which is go
cautious and start rolling it out
because it you can't fully trust some
test Suite that you run desn't team have
built a torture test and even that one
is not good enough but that's also
expensive dollars wise TimeWise yeah so
I think this notion of how well or how
hard it is to assess how well your
product works is a big deal and I think
uh Source graph RAB really highlighted
that as well in terms of the testing and
the creation of code search and finding
the right context absolutely in cont
yeah context was King really there but I
think with the breadth of the various
tools that actually both Peter and
rishab talked about both at tab n and
and Source graph the evaluation we
covered a lot and of course rishab is
the head of AI and lives in that ml
space and so much of his work is really
about that evaluation to to to Really
provide that model like that really is
providing that output which is relevant
to to the input and context is a big
piece of this but we he was talking
about the kind of zero to one on that
and how useful that was but yeah there
are a ton of that and yeah very valuable
I think uh it's interesting to take this
now back into the consumer side and I
think that very much shown through as
well which is as a builder of those
tools okay only a subset of people
listening to this might be actively
building llm based tools although more
and more of us might be in that position
later on uh but as a consumer of those
tools you get the same experience as
well and and even for the people that
are at the Forefront and are building
these llm tools it is hard for them to
actually take those on and embrace them
for these same reasons is because they
take those tools and they can't trust
really that they would work well and
some of that manifes in once again we
keep referring to Dez he was just
brilliant in his sort of quotes and his
talk about being able to to embrace
tools but also Amir touched about touch
at that a fair bit when he talked about
the different tools and different
domains and where is it that you can
maybe be comfortable with with those
tools and I guess you've been filling it
in your your own tools that you've
beening for this podcast and for Tesla
for this podcast as well I mean so we
use a ton of kind of like AI tooling
both in the editing and AI powered AI
sorry AI powered tooling absolutely yeah
to to to edit and actually build content
around this we did a ton of trying to
actually identify where the most
interesting shorts and quotes could be
to be honest I've in in some areas
they've been great time Savers in others
they give me an answer but it's never
the right answer so like shorts is the
great or put in quotes the five most
interesting 10 most interesting pieces
from a podcast it very rarely picks the
10 that I would pick and I think I don't
know whether it's just the intent it
doesn't understand the intent it could
be from a prompt perspective but it's
not a time saving for me even more so I
still there's still a balance here
between me putting my kind of like
knowledge and intelligence into this and
then using the AI assisted tooling to
actually assist me really and time saave
where I can be helped but yeah I I feel
like
in this space it's not quite there yet
yeah and it's frustrating right cuz we
want to lean in we want to be early
adopters we're Believers in the
destination yeah and we've invested
upfront right you spend a lot of time
trying to both pick tools Even build
some tools write some things on it and
they're so close they're so tantalizing
there's still moments of Amazement as
you run
them but on average they really they
don't quite make the cut so I think you
have to what can you do really as a
consumer I think you have to keep trying
you have to moderate your use so don't
rely on these tools working but I think
you need to come back to the well again
again to to always to to find the cases
in which it works but fundamentally I
think today the cases in which it works
the best is when it still works as an
assistant so it offers you something it
sometimes it would save you time but
don't uh build your plan assuming that
it would work yeah I I I'm so with you
on that kind of like revisiting the well
because it's amazing how fast the where
we were 6 months ago we wouldn't even it
close to where we are today think that
they could work absolutely so I think
revisiting making sure that our
assumptions of where we were six months
ago are actually still true and whether
we can actually improve where we are
today so what was your what's your kind
of next takea away from the bulk of the
episodes that we had this month so I
think Co generation was one of the first
categories that we talked about and one
of the one of the really interesting
themes that kind of came up again and
again was context and I think context is
really King in terms of being able to
take understand the intent and then
actually provide a valuable answer based
on the right context I think there's one
topic where I was talking with with
Peter from tab 9 where we covered how
much is too much context what is the
right amount of context and it's
interesting that you can give too much
context so that actually you're
providing so much information it's hard
for the l l to actually provide the
right answer because it's almost flooded
with too much information but providing
the right amount of context will allow
it to actually be far more accurate in
in providing that answer I think Dez was
also he talked about bad context as well
as good context right I Lov kind of that
other quote yet another great phrasing
from Dez but he talked about how a
common experience for intercom customers
that try out Finn their sort of
autonomous AI agent is that they find
that Finn mirrors or reflects their
knowledge base very well but lo and
behold the knowledge base itself is out
of date and it turns out that there's a
bunch of voodoo knowledge uh that
happens Shadow knowledge that happens
within the support team that helps
support reps know what information there
is up to date and what isn't and that
Finn might lack that subtlety and so
they need to go and fix that and so
first of all I I think that's
interesting it's very easy to understand
and I think everybody can relate to the
fact the knowledge base is out of date
your docs are out of date all of those
things uh as you start building all
those uh that's significant I think a
bit more subtle is to think about your
code and to think about how uh I guess
he says it crap in crap out uh if your
code is full of bad practices that you
actually don't want to maintain then lo
and behold if you train on your code you
might be replicating practices that are
not really uh what you desire so it's
interesting the sort of balance of the
the default sort of perspective maybe in
the world of llms and AI is give me more
context I will be able to understand
your needs more I will be able to
personalize customize it better uh but
at the same time there's a certain
element of flooding and too much and not
being able to separate the important
context from the less important one and
there's an element of be careful what
you wish for right yeah if you give me
too much history I might make history
repeat itself yeah absolutely and
actually there's a couple of ways we can
see this when we think about code
completion obviously training needs to
happen on existing code and it's pulling
know many many tools pull from open
source Library open source libraries
there's going to be good code there's
going to be poor code there's going to
be security problems and so forth it's
going to be trying to replicate that
code that it's seeing but also when we
think about existing issues in our own
code where we're providing context on
top of that training it's going to
effectively see similar antipatterns
problems coding issues security
potentially issues that it could
replicate because hey I saw you did that
over there and you want to do something
similar let me use a similar style of
code and so yeah craping cra out it's
exactly the same it's exactly the same
theme and you're it's interesting to
think that this happens at multiple
layers there is the notion of these
systems have been trained on the world's
code yeah so problems or patterns that
repeat in the world's code might repeat
in the very models themselves in the new
network uh but also as you go down the
the the rabbit hole and you customize
and you personalize to your environment
then if you train on a customer code
base you might replicate patterns over
there and I think actually one of the
latest studies that you did Simon at
sneak showed how if there's a tab open
with with a code pattern that happens to
be vulnerable then co-pilot is more
likely to replicate it so at any as
local or AS Global a resolution these
llms they replicate they they build on
data and so we need to be mindful of
that yeah absolutely and there was one
interesting other piece going thinking
more about the kind of context that we
give in llm uh speaking with Devon and
he built the dosu tool which was amazing
for open source maintainers and users in
terms of maybe they create an issue a
user was to create an issue against an
open source project and it may take time
for that maintainer to even start
looking at that issue and and and
performing a response maybe it's user
error maybe it's something else and
there's context which allows dosu to be
able to provide an answer within minutes
to that user now provided the right
context it can say oh here's the answer
but it's in the documentation or in fact
one of the one of the really interesting
where it wasn't in documentation but
there were actually test cases which
were saying this is what I expect and so
Dosey would look at that and say okay
this is the expected Behavior I can tell
the user this is what you should be
doing however there's also bad context
whereby it was inferring behavior from
the code and actually while that
behavior is a possible workaround it
isn't actually the way that maintainer
wanted that person to use so there was a
case whereby it's actually using the
context but not in the right way that
the maintainer the user wants that to be
a great example of a case in which yes
this works today and this is the pattern
of what happens today but I'm trying to
change that I'm trying to get people to
do it the right way absolutely it's the
sort of the core principle is whenever
you make more information available more
options available to anything then
selection and sorting becomes a problem
discovery of the correct of the better
object on it it could be like whatever
it's snake we talked about
vulnerabilities hey if I tell you about
too many vulnerabilities they might be
all right but there's too much for me to
handle I want know which ones are right
it might be about discovering Spotify of
sort of songs and you want to pick the
songs that are most right for me and to
an extent is if you give me more
knowledge about your code if you need
give me more knowledge about your system
suddenly the problem is no longer
availability of knowledge but rather
prioritization saying which knowledge is
more important and the input of how
actually a user will actually not just
provide the context but you know provide
their request that's going to be
massively different depending on the
tool usage or where that is actually
being run whether it's in an IDE whether
it's in a PR or or somewhere else there
was a lot of discussion that happened I
think with particularly with the de chat
again we keep going back to that Dez
session but around the different type of
input with maybe chat UI as a way to to
inter interact versus maybe an
autocomplete much more a quicker line by
line versus something that you actually
build up with a chat UI I found that
really interesting the basically Des
made the argument that to an extent
completion is a form of chat you are
just instead of telling me what you want
in words you are telling me by providing
me more context as I type and I found
that super interesting I'm not entirely
sure I agree I'm still digesting it I
think uh to an extent maybe the
meta understanding is that any
interaction with llm is about the choice
of what information are you providing me
how much did you invest in giving me
context we keep coming back to that word
uh but context and alongside context in
intent so how much did you tell me to
understand your surrounding but also how
much did you explain to me what is it
that you want in words or in terms or in
other data structures that I can
understand and the better you do that
the better the llm is able to give you
the result that you want and in a chat
context you can be more explicit in what
you're asking but you're providing maybe
less context and the model is such that
you're expecting the llm to give you an
answer and give it right away versus a
completion an environment in which your
intent is implicit you're typing along
you're providing information and if
before your language and how you phrase
that maybe your prompt engineering
skills in the chat came to to shine and
if you were autocom completing it's
almost like how well are you completing
that code are you writing a comment and
then expecting a code completing tool to
to provide you with that text which is
really quite close to chat at that point
are you just typing along code and
you're expecting it to infer so they're
basically all just variations on it and
I think what's interesting there is to
think if you're building a solution that
leverages it because this was all in the
context of is it easier to think about
introducing llms into a tool that is
already chat-based or not and whether in
the context of code pull requests that
are maybe a little bit more chatty
asynchronous chat are more amendable to
success versus code completions and it
was challenging that
legitimately but in in the context of
that if you're building some llm
capability really the question you
should ask yourself is what are are the
correct ways for a user to provide me
with their intent what is it they want
me to do and with the context necessary
for me to be successful and I think in
chatting with rashab about the various
pieces that that Cody did the
differences in how you would use or how
you would request information from anlm
here for example in code completion you
would expect an answer very quickly
however if it was something beyond that
and you're actually getting more back
maybe it's a test generation or
something like that it allows the llm to
actually have far more time to generate
that answer and he it was a really
interesting conversation about how fast
what is that latency that you need
before encode completion if you part
surpass that that latency it would
frustrate a developer whereas in other
cases you can actually have a you can
actually spend much much more time and
get a much more accurate answer for a
bigger task and that's acceptable and I
think when we think about you the the
the chat UI versus autocomplete and
things like that it provides you know
the differences in how long and what
accuracy it can provide you with yeah so
many variables yeah additionally on that
when we talked about intent which is
really important one of the one of the
topics that came up was around the
intent um of a question to a chat GPT
versus the intent of some a much more
specific tool and it's much much harder
when you actually ask something of chat
GPT because the the breadth of what a
chat GPT can expect to get is obviously
going to be much wider than if you're
asking something in an IDE it's going to
be a coding based question Etc um and
this really brings us to the kind of
scope of what you would expect from
these AI assistants and I think one of
the things that we talked about is
particularly with Amir there are really
nice categories that we talked about of
it's great for a tool to exist in this
AI code assistant as well as a
documentation tool would be great as
well as a a testing tool but actually
some of the vendors that we've been
talking to they're actually quite Broad
in what they offer as well right it's
actually a little bit funny because you
talked to air who is looking at it from
a consumer perspective from an investor
perspect perspective and he looks at the
markets and he has really valuable
delineations of saying this is a
category or a class of capabilities that
people can do and I think very useful
and they make sense to me right you're
going to have your sort of coding
assistance your code completions you're
going to have your AI documentations
you're going to have your AI tests
you're going to have your operations
stuff and then you talk to I think
pretty much every one of the vendors
that we spoke to says oh we do all of
those yeah and they don't straight up
say we do all of them but I think when
they come down to the technology there's
so much overlap and so much uh so many
open questions around what is the right
scope of these products and so whether
it is around Codi that indeed started
from code search and they understand
that code and but now we're talking
about coding assistance and they do they
do testing a lot of the conversation was
around the testing uh tab n the same
they fine they will index the sort of
the code and they have some test and
they and you look around and I think
it's I think it's really interesting to
me it shows two things one the
Technologies are very intertwined and
once you are able to understand the code
understand what needs to be done then uh
all sorts of paths open and all of them
try to grab it and the second is that
it's there's no set expectations yet
from a customer perspective on what do
they want to get where so there's
no nobody has had the time to
demonstrate that they are so
dramatically better at this slice of
functionality and that is so much more
valuable that the fact that they are so
much better means something that is
worth a best of breed
solution and a lot of the value is still
in that 8020 it says hey I can generate
documentations with
llm maybe I can already get to there
uh and so I think there's a lot of uh
opportunity like a lot of these vendors
are are just trying to seize a broader
broader scope and I think time will tell
I don't know exactly where the lines
would be drawn and I think it's still
useful for us as we talk about
development to talk about discrete tools
regardless of whether single vendors
will provide them talk about discrete
pieces of functionality but it is it's
quite hard to to find vendors now that
contain themselves consolidation this is
interesting because even with our
histories as well when we when we think
about tooling companies we've been
involved in consolidation is a really
key important thing for example if if I
was a developer that wanted to do all of
these things anyway and I will want to
do them whether it's testing whether
it's documentation whether it's the code
completion the AI assistance that help
there would I want three
tools or or or would I just want one
Consolidated tool that does it all for
me and if you have different vendors
that are slightly better at different
capabilities is it actually nicer for me
to have that one experience that that
does it all and I guess the autonomy
here also plays a part in this as
whether I'm using it directly or whether
the some process is happening in the
background for and I think I think uh
autonomy plays a role in general the the
question is really how much value do you
get from a tool that is better uh and I
think we just don't know as consumers we
don't know the answer to that yet and so
know when like the the main question
that we ask is do we want AI to generate
say documentation for us right do we
want AI to generate tests for us that's
that's the question that we ask and then
if we have a tool that is already
available and also if we've especially
if we've ended up training it on our
code base or do something like that then
it's available to us and it is
convenient for us to use that and
because we don't know what good looks
like yet nobody does then we default to
think okay this is this represents what
I seeing here as I try to generate test
is now coloring my sense of how much can
be done and also because a lot of these
capabilities they have some anchor of
understanding the code that is shared
amidst these different capabilities and
then beyond that core anchor I think
many of them end up being a relatively
shallow layer on top of the core llms
and then that additional understanding
and so it's a relatively low lift so
small lift for these companies to
provide them and so I guess if I was to
wager I would think that we'll see a lot
of that consolidation and all-in-one
come out and I think in some cases we'll
find that things are very tightly
intertwined I think we heard this a
little bit on Cody and spoiler alert
some of this comes up in a conversation
with with itamar from codium that that
will Air soon in those conversations you
hear a lot about for instance the diff
the relationship between testing and
code generation okay if you understand
the code and you know what is correct
can you generate the right code to it I
can buy into that at the same time other
domains maybe documentation will come
out as something that has enough
sophistication to it enough unique needs
to it that we can see that a certain
subset of tools are are better at it you
know but we just don't know so I think
they will be Consolidated and then some
will break out and then we'll have the
regular consolidation device which is
okay now we have a whole set of tools
after a bunch of years and yeah some are
known as best of breed but we'll have
the regular decisions on what's we we
would know what good looks like and
we'll make a conscious decision whether
we care or do we prefer the fewer
vendors yeah and and you know what I
think is really going to be important
here I think data is going to be king
here in terms of the data of
understanding
behavior of how things are using the
application let me go into a couple of
examples let's say you had an AI tool
which was a monitoring tool for example
can take production data about where
code paths which code paths are the hot
code paths perhaps youve got behavioral
data that show which areas of the code
base are being changed most by
developers perhaps you've got testing
data about which tests which areas of
the code are actually finding the
greatest number of uh issues or security
data about vulnerabilities all of this
data can like really help us in terms of
the other tools recognize where they
should where they should focus on more
an example if I have a AI tool or AI
assisted tool that that looks at
monitoring data and understands the code
flows and where my users are going
through it understands the golden paths
the hot paths that's where my AI testing
tool needs to focus if my AI testing
tool is identifying issues and actually
code fixes are occurring because of a
certain type of flow my AI uh code
completion assistant my AI assistant
there needs to make sure it's not
suggesting code which in that similar
vein so I feel like there's a a lot of
data here which actually makes the value
of that consolidation really useful if
that data is being shared yeah I I agree
and I think I guess if I was to use a
startup par lens over here I'll talk
about power from the seven Powers by
Hamilton Helmer where he talks about all
sorts of strategic differentiators or or
advantages
and that data is one of those in which
you can it's really
about how much better situated you are
to deliver value to your customer and so
data is one aspect do I already have
data that is valuable and therefore I
can do something better sometimes it's
just distribution it's just okay I'm I'm
already installed on everybody's
desktops and maybe that gives me access
to data but it also just gives me an
opportunity to offer you that tool
sometimes it is just a commercial
relationship sometimes it is an
investment that has been made in
indexing the code I guess it's a form of
data that is technically available to
some other vendor as well but it
requires the customer to have invest Ed
time in connecting it to all the right
places and and customizing and tuning it
or defining policies so all of these
things are advantages and I think in
that stage we're coming back to the
classic startup game which is do do the
disruptors acquire distribution before
the incumbents acquire Innovation do we
what happens first and I think that's
interesting but I think the in in if we
go back to talk about the scope of these
AI Dev tools to me the primary
conclusion from the conversations and it
was almost the conflict between the very
first or second episode that we had
around air so in such a great fashion
dividing uh these different tools and
then how every single vendor you talk to
is just messes this up and almost like
unwilling to accept that that bundling I
think goes to show that we need to
assess them but we should expect that
the tools when we go to them they don't
quite fall in line until some lines
clarify yeah which I think think is fine
right because we will have needs in
these different categories and there
will be tools and vendors that will
address multiple of those needsa now I
expecting these tools to only fit in one
category it's probably a dream or maybe
a hallucination guy which leads me
incredibly nicely see how smooth that
was guys incredible I am aren't I I am
or at least maybe that's the artificial
intelligence piece of me that's uh yeah
no I didn't I'm going to ignore the
teleprompter that was that was a pure
human int pure
close enough at times yeah so
hallucinations and how much we are happy
to accept that an AI tool will
hallucinate and provide us with
something that is incorrect or a
hallucination there was a really nice
quote I think but a very interesting
discussion from Dez that you spoke with
about how willing you are to accept
hallucinations and it will provide you
with other value right but the pain of
course is you get some crap
hallucination which is either
meaningless or nonsense or whatever
right or just straight up deceiving and
I I think so it's interesting I find in
general intercom is much further along
than most providers in building llm
based tools and I find a lot of their
learnings to be just a step ahead in
terms of having faced reality and made
it work and not surprisingly this was
describing how they contained a lot of
the hallucinations or a lot of their
work was to contain hallucinations so
that if you're coming to a place and
you're interacting with a support bot
then you know when you get an answer
you'd be able to trust it but it was
very clear that if you allowed Finn to
hallucinate more you can resolve more
cases if you can get more creative and
the problem is how do you get more
creative with without losing
trustworthiness and I think it's really
interesting I got got my product mind
spinning a little bit to say
are there ways are there patterns as an
industry that we can do that we can find
that help us roll that or engage the
customer in that conversation right
would customers accept that they ask
Finn say a question and Finn gives them
an says they don't it doesn't know or
you know provides them an answer and
that does address they're doing it and
it asks them do you want me to try and
get more creative keep in mind my
answers might become less accurate or
even sometimes hallucina
and it's I don't know it's interesting
it doesn't seem entirely obvious to me
that the answer is no that customers
will be unwilling to accept it at the
same time sometimes maybe it's too much
complexity and also maybe it's a time to
switch to a human and maybe that's okay
and and that was really interesting when
you said an AI answer or or an answer
that comes from an llm saying I don't
know and in my chat with Devin and by
Devon I mean the founder of do must be
so awfully for de if you're confused in
if you're listening to it and you
haven't listened to the episode Devin is
the CEO and founder of dosu which is AI
tool that has nothing to do with it I
didn't just do a podcast with the AI
software engineer and it's yeah
alongside it being one of the most known
in AI engineering because it was
introduced as a tool named Devon that is
a engineer yeah must be awfully
confusing so Devon the person the human
intelligence the human de de now he was
one of the really interesting things
that he mentioned is that llms don't
like answering I don't know right right
you have to really be clear in the
training with them that there needs to
be some some limit or some bar whereby
if they don't have a level of confidence
uh that is that is above that bar it
should say I don't know you need to talk
to a human or or something like that now
the the the interesting piece there
there is really if it doesn't know it
tries to make up an answer it doesn't
like saying no if it can't and and
actually there was a really interesting
thing that I was doing at Tesla as well
where I was in the blog creation stage
where we're looking at building up
content I thought wouldn't it be nice if
I wrote a little a little agent in cre
aai which is one of the tools that we
use for for our content building and and
that to what that agent did is it looked
at the Tesla blog and tried to identify
additional resources additional content
pieces and it said oh here's some
related content that you might want to
look at now of course no is a perfectly
acceptable answer there there there was
no related content but it didn't want to
give me the answer no so what it did was
even before we launched the blog it
would come back with five or six
different blogs that didn't exist great
titles by the way as well with URLs
saying here is an amazing piece of
related content it couldn't find an
answer but it wanted to please me it
wanted to Delight me with an answer so
it generated all these blogs that didn't
exist and said here is here is your
answer and I'm sure it was just as
confident with that answer as if it was
real or whether it was hallucinating and
making these and I I think it's it's
fascinating and learning how to deal and
manage with that it's interesting like
one bit there I think it was also like
making up some co-pilot features like it
was very much like inventing new reality
not just new content and it's
interesting sometimes to think hey those
things that it's hallucinating are
things that should exist so that was
already interesting one of my one of my
friends
he was asking an llm usage of a specific
library and it suggested oh yeah you
should use the API here of course that
Library didn't have an API at all but it
provided all the information about this
is what the API looks like this is how
you invoke it and then there was two
things Lan was first of all like a
little bit frustrated that hey this
doesn't exist you're just hallucinating
this up but then the second piece was
maybe it should have that API cuz you
know what this would have been really
would happy to have it so I think that's
really interesting and yeah and just cap
that is
indeed in their maturity journey I
didn't see it in action but as was
commenting that Finn tells you how
confident it is in its answer and it
almost balances this I don't know so but
if I was to try and guess here's the
information I have and here's the so it
shouldn't make up information but at
least low confidence information so
there are ux patterns that I think we
can figure out and I think that's us as
humans need to be more comfortable with
that as well in understanding okay this
I am talking to an um agent in the
background it has provided me with
something I recognize that the
temperature is up it will hallucinate
more but the confidence is really
important there so I recognize I will
get a better interaction with it but I
need to be mindful of the comply and
it's a a challenge for the ux folks
because if we if we don't figure it out
then you end up either needing to be
entirely accurate which in turn reduces
the usefulness of the llms or we're
sometimes deceiving our users which is
clearly not an awesome thing to do Guy
this is has been great it's been a
really strong month of of sessions
really great kickoff for the podcast um
a couple of things that are going to be
changing actually we're we we're looking
at and we are adjusting based on what we
have learned and feedback that we've had
around the podcast my sessions are going
to be changing just slightly whereby I'm
going to have I'm going to be releasing
two sessions per guest back to back on
the same day and actually the Devon
session Devin's session rather showed
this actually where whereby we have a
chat first of all about some of the
topics that we're going to that we're
covering and then we're going to do a
Hands-On session so we're actually going
to go deeper it's going to be a Hands-On
screen share so better with video versus
just audio but this is going to be a
very much more Hands-On Dev focused
session so keep a lookout for that going
forward you've already recorded another
couple of sessions what can our
listeners look forward to coming first
of all I would say that if you're
listening to this on the podcast these
sessions that Simon is describing will
be especially best viewed in a visual
but we do intend for the conversation
that comes before that to be very kind
of a podcast friendly as well and we
would welcome feedback we're still at
contact tess. if you have thoughts about
how you want us to change that and then
we've had since the joy of recorded
podcast we did record a bunch of great
episodes that coming up I will mention
itar I've already alluded to that itamar
the co-founder and CEO of codium AI
we'll talk about AI testing and more and
Simon will add some some real world some
live session of it and had a great
conversation with Jason Warner
previously the CTO of of GitHub where
they built he was there as they built
actions and co-pilot and more and has
done a lot of great things and right now
is running one of the top foundation
models in in that are code focused
called poolside and we talk a lot about
what is code generation why does it work
where is it headed generic versus code
specific lots and lots of great insights
from Jason those and many not many but a
few more episodes coming this month
it'll be another great month tune in
yeah absolutely guy pleasure doing our
first monthly Roundup indeed this was
fun and I hope you all join us for all
the episodes this coming mon
amazing thanks for tuning in join us
next time on the AI native Dev brought
to you by tessla
[Music]